ADRIENNE MARIE GEIS

951 Powhatan St., ALEXANDRIA, VA ♦ C: 17033070734 ♦ adriennegeis@gmail.com ♦ US Citizen

– Professional Summary *–*

Multi-disciplined Executive with 20+ years of experience in delivering results for small and large businesses. I am very high-energy and have a passion for motivating focused teams toward goal attainment. Known for adhering to high ethical standards and embracing new challenges. Expertise in leadership, strategy, decision-making and relationship-building, and experience in all aspects of running a small to mid-sized for-profit services company.

SKILLS —

- Leadership
- Strategic Planning
- Expert Project Management
- Vendor Relationships
- HR Administration
- Contract Administration
- · Financial Planning and Reporting

- KPI Development / Delivery
- Outstanding People Management
- Budget Administration
- Corporate Accounting ESOP and HR Audit coordination
- Exceptional Interpersonal Communication
- Accounting
- Issue Resolution

WORK HISTORY -

COMSCORE, INC RESTON, VA

Vice President Business Operations

March 2019 - June 2019

Consultant AMG Consulting LLC & Fast Data Connect, Inc.

September 2018 – March 2019

Successfully stood up a new Program Office for a 700+ person organization in a Big Data advertising measurement corporation. Facilitated CITO's vision for the development of repeatable methods to organize, prioritize, communicate and measure the success of development and infrastructure projects. Managed, with staff, a budget of approximately \$130M, including monthly reporting, procurement, vendor and asset management.

TERRALOGIC INTEGRATED SYSTEMS ANALYSTS, INC.

ALEXANDRIA, VA

Executive Vice President,

January 2016 to September 2018

Promoted from Vice President of Administration

2014 to 2016

Promoted from Vice President and Special Assistant to CEO

2009 to 2013

Facilitated CEO's corporate vision by consolidating redundant functions and continually streamlining overhead expenses, resulting in continual annual savings of approximately 20% over the past five fiscal years. Savings were realized in lease space, infrastructure, support systems and personnel.

Successfully supported and facilitated the CEO's exit strategy and the subsequent corporate acquisition while maintaining the strictest confidentiality standards and providing all relevant due diligence materials to broker, acquirer, and all legal and compliance related vendors.

Upon the former President's retirement in 2015 recognized across the organization as the senior leader and decision-maker for all internal functions and capital expenditures. Demonstrated cross-functional leadership while maintaining relationships with external vendors and stakeholders. My ability to make day-to-day decisions and resolve issues freed up the CEO to focus on corporate strategic priorities.

A few highlights from my daily responsibilities include the following:

- As ESOP Administrator, ensured contributions, distributions, valuations, accounting, filings and expense management
 maintained in accordance with plan documentation. Primary interface with Legal, Audit, Valuation firm, Trustee and
 Record-keeper for preparation of regulatory documents. Led effort to close ESOP at Company acquisition.
- Executive in charge of Contracts Administration and management of commercial and government contracts and relationships, including negotiations and compliance with vendors and clients. Successfully negotiated for favorable payment terms with Fortune 100 clients.
- Executive in charge of HR management, hiring/termination, insurance and benefit administration. Maintained 100% compliance with Federal and state regulations, obtained a WC audit premium refund every year for the past 8 years running, and had no adverse EEO finding during my tenure as HR executive.
- Active participation in all Strategic Planning and Business Development efforts of the corporation.
- Responsible for all cash management for the corporation.
- Led lease and facility planning and management for corporation.
- Executive in charge of IT and infrastructure planning and strategic management.
- Oversight and administration of financial and accounting functions to include reporting, compliance, and all aspects of obtaining and retaining financing with lenders.

Vice President Finance and Accounting,

2006 to 2009

- Completed financial reporting for corporation on a monthly, quarterly, and annual basis with team of seven.
- Primary responsibility for all accounting and financing functions including A/R, A/P, PR, G/L and Cash management.
- Primary corporate interface on annual corporate Audit.
- Managed all cash functions for the corporation on a multi-million-dollar line of credit Successfully reduced collections time from over 75 days to approximately 45 and kept all collections within terms of the borrowing base.
- Successfully led and implemented an outsourcing effort, including the consolidation of multiple complex in-house accounting systems onto Quickbooks Pro, resulting in over 50% annual systems cost savings.

Corporate Technical Director,

2004 to 2006

- Leader of corporate network and application development, staff of five. Successfully consolidated internal systems, planned necessary infrastructure upgrades, and simplified network configuration while increasing availability and reliability.
- In charge of budget, scheduling, strategic development and tactical implementation of corporation's information system organization (CBIS).
- Additionally, managed corporation's purchasing and logistics function and lead financial analysis of corporation's operating budget.

VERIZON COMMUNICATIONS

1989 to 2002

Director Tier 2 and Trouble Administration Systems (Wholesale)

2000 to 2002

Led organization of 90+ contributors, managed multiple software releases, and a simultaneous architecture conversion to J2EE. Directed separate PIC (Preferred Interexchange Carrier) system development according to release schedule. Led trouble management help desk for Wholesale organization. Managed group budget ranging from \$5M - \$10M.

- Handled staff and budget reductions while maintaining deliverable schedule for new single-architecture trouble management system which combined several separate middleware applications onto one new platform Moved all PIC system contractor work from on-site to India in a six-month timeframe.
- Used as a benchmark to begin to offshore technical staff within an additional six months.
- Projected savings were over \$1M and included redeployment/retraining of approximately 15 technical resources.
- Developed and enhanced help-desk processes and procedures for the Wholesale organization.
- Transitioned help desk from entirely contractor staffed to entirely internally staffed within 6-month time period.

Senior Manager, Billing and Customer Care Systems (expressTRAK)

1999 to 2000

Managed software implementations; including planning, tracking, executive-level metric reporting, issue management and process improvement for more than two dozen billing and ordering applications. Managed additional team of seven developers doing "triage" work on troubles for customer care and related applications. Demonstrated leadership and decision-making ability by managing multiple simultaneous releases with minimal direct reports and multiple chains of command.

- Considered "Mission Control" for release implementations which occurred weekly.
- All releases successfully executed.

- Recognized as a department finalist for Verizon's annual IT (team) achievement award for successful coordination of long-distance database segmentation project.
- Introduced implementation processes and procedures that ensured successful implementation of online and batch processes within a designated downtime window.
- Implemented continuous improvement processes.
- Owned hotline management, escalation, and management of billing system troubles.

Programmer Analyst, Manager	1989 to 1999
EDUCATION —	
Certificate in Women's Leadership (course): April 2016	DARDEN, UVA
MBA: Finance, 1996 High Honors	ST JOSEPH'S UNIVERSITY
B.S : Business Computer Information Systems, Economics, 1989	ST. VINCENT COLLEGE
High Honors	
CLEARANCE:	SECRET, TS Eligible
AFFILIATIONS —	
	han Daard of Dinastons 2016 to assument
President, Board of Directors, BalletNova Center for Dance 2018, Mem	ber, Board of Directors 2016 to current